LULU CAO

Kansas City, MO | 816-974-7106 | <u>caolulu000@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn Profile | GitHub Profile

OBJECTIVE

I'm a full-stack web developer with 2 years of experiences, seeking a Software Engineer position. I'm a highly driven individual who thrives on learning and growing. I excel in setting and achieving goals, complemented by a proactive mindset to tackle challenges.

SKILLS

Vue.js	React.js	JavaScript
Django	Express.js	TypeORM
MySQL	CSS	Docker
AWS	Heroku	Git

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer I

Dec 2022 – Present

Dimensional Innovations

Overland Park, Kansas

- o Implement designs for a variety of web apps with Vue.js, Electron.js, and React.js
- Develop CMS and API within each project, using Django, Admin.js, Express.js, and TypeORM
- Integrate WSS communication across multiple applications and devices
- o Deploy to GitLab and Heroku and release artifacts to AWS S3

Volunteer Full Stack Developer

Jun 2022 – Dec 2022

KC Digital Drive

Kansas City, Missouri

- Created an app that allows the public to report illegal trash dumping over SMS using Twilio Studio
- o Created an Express server to record reports, download images, and extract EXIF data
- o Improved front end using React to display and create records
- o Used AWS Amplify, API Gateway, DynamoDB, Lambda, and IAM to implement authentication, enable admins to manually create records, and automatically store records

Technical Co-Founder

Nov 2021 - Feb 2023

Symposia, Inc.

Remote | Iowa

- Used Ruby on Rails to create templates and manage routes
- o Used CSS, Bootstrap, and JavaScript to implement product design and business logic
- Used Ruby Minitest and Heroku logs to test and debug
- o Deployed to staging and production environments on Heroku

Development Intern

Jan 2022 - Feb 2022

Trivial, Inc.

Remote | California

- o Expanded Trivial's list of supported platforms with features that allow users to communicate over Slack, view shipments from Ship&Co, and send orders to Printful stores
- o Wrote tests for every new feature using the Mocha JS test framework
- o Created and iterated pull requests for every new feature based on feedback
- o Utilized Postman along with AWS Cloudwatch logs to test and debug new features

Adjunct Professor of Philosophy

Jan 2022 - May 2023

Metropolitan Community College

Kansas City, Missouri

- o Created syllabi and presented diverse perspectives and arguments
- Facilitated in-class discussions and debates among high school, college, and non-traditional students
- o Advised students on an individual basis for their academic work and growth
- o Taught 7 classes and 170 students in total

EDUCATION

0	Western Michigan University, Michigan	Sep 2019 – May 2021
	M.A. in Philosophy	GPA 3.95/4.00
0	Salisbury University, Maryland	Sep 2018 – May 2019
	B.A. in Interdisciplinary Studies	GPA 4.00/4.00
0	Anqing Normal University, China	Sep 2015 – Jul 2019
	B.A. in English	(top 5%) GPA 3.62/4.00

VOLUNTEER

0	Tech Talks Program Director, Kansas City Women in Technology	Dec 2023 – Present
0	Curriculum Director, Kansas City Women in Technology	Aug 2023 – Present
0	Diversity and Inclusion Committee Co-Chair	Mar 2023 – Present
0	Communication Volunteer, Freelance Exchange of Kansas City	Jul 2022 – Dec 2022

CERTIFICATE

o Girl Develop It Hackathon Winner

Nov 2021

INTERESTS

- Volunteering
- o Adventuring
- Philosophizing
- o Reading